TENGOKU-DAIMAKYO
茨城和奈良有多遠？
Far enough.
夠遠了
But Ibaraki is closer than Nara.
但比起奈良，茨城比較近
THE WALLED TOWN
《圍牆小鎮》
Nara, Bakinara, Bakinara, Ibaraki.
奈良，巴崎奈良，巴崎奈良，茨城
Nara, Ibaraki, Nara, Ibaraki.
奈良，茨城，奈良，茨城
Nara, Baraki, Baraki.
奈良，巴拉崎，巴拉崎
Nara, Kibara, Nara, Ibaraki, Nara--
奈良，崎巴拉，奈良，茨城，奈良
Shut up with the "narabaki, narabaki!"
不要再「奈良巴崎、奈良巴崎」說個不停
But five hours is so long.
但五個小時很長耶
What are you? A kid?
你還是個孩子嗎？
Can't we get there faster?
沒有辦法快一點到那裡嗎？
Well, it might take longer than five hours.
這個嘛，有可能會不只五小時
-What?
-什麼？
Well, the earthquake made the roads…
地震讓路面都…
Then, how long is it gonna take?
那麼，到底需要多久？
I'm not sure.
我不太確定
That's weird.
很可疑
You're not taking us to your friends to get back at us, are you?
你不是打算把我們帶到你朋友那裡 報復我們吧？
I'd never do that.
我絕對不會做這種事
Didn't you mean what you said earlier?
你們剛剛只是胡說的嗎？
ABOUT TWO HOURS AGO
（大約兩個小時前）
You scared me!
你嚇到我了啦
What do you mean?
你在說什麼啦？
You said you wanted to see if the baby is still alive.
你們剛剛說想知道那個嬰兒是否還活著
The story about the breeding pig is true.
有關種豬的故事是真的
I was going to take revenge once I got everything ready.
等到萬事俱備之後，我就要展開報復
Is that why you wanted my gun?
所以你才會想要我的槍嗎？
Sis, this tattoo is the real thing.
姊，這個刺青是真的
Let me ask you one thing. Where is it?
回答我一個問題，那個地方在哪裡？
On roads that are in good condition, about five hours.
如果挑路況好的路走，大概需要五小時
It's around here.
就在這附近
Isn't it practically in Ibaraki?
那不就剛好是位於茨城嗎？
Isn't that what you call "perfect pitch"?
這不就是所謂的「絕對音感」嗎？
It's "timing."
是「碰巧」啦
I didn't steal it.
我沒有偷走
I-- I'm sorry.
對不起
Are you okay?
妳還好吧？
But does this mean you'll trust me now?
但這表示妳現在願意相信我了嗎？
Juichi.
充一
I'm still only coming with you to see if the baby's alive.
我只會陪你去確認那個嬰兒是否還活著
That's good enough.
這樣就夠了
Let's hide the car here and go. Then--
我們把車藏在這裡之後就走吧，然後…
Hey, don't stand out so much!
兩位，低調一點
Miss, wait a minute!
小姐，等等我
There's something I need to check.
我得先確認一件事
You jerk!
你這個混球
Don't feel up the chest of another man's woman!
她是我的女人，不准亂摸她的胸部
I-- I'm sorry!
對不起
Who is whose woman?
誰是誰的女人？
That's not it. I didn't notice yesterday,
不是那樣的啦，我昨天沒注意到
but your large chest could put you in danger.
但妳的大胸部可能會給妳帶來危險
Why?
為什麼？
Women with big chests are hated in that town.
那個小鎮討厭胸部大的女人
Please keep your jacket zipped up.
請務必把外套拉鍊拉上
Some had to cut theirs off to live there.
有些人為了住在那裡還得把胸部切除
SELF-IMPOSED RESTRAINT
（自我約束）
Why would women do that to each other?
為什麼女人要對彼此做這種事？
They're a crazy bunch that imprisoned a young boy and tattooed him!
她們是一群把年輕男孩關起來 在他身上刺青的瘋女人
Who knows what they're thinking?
誰知道她們在想什麼？
Now I'm worried. I'm going with you!
我開始擔心了，我跟妳一起去
You idiot! It's even more dangerous to go with a man!
你白癡啊，帶著一個男人同行更危險
If you want to go, I've got something good.
如果你想跟的話，我有個好辦法
-Maybe a little to the left? -Oh, you're right.
-要不向左邊移一點？ -你說的對
How does it look?
看起來如何？
W-- What the… You're p-- pretty.
這…你很漂亮
Why don't you look happy?
妳為什麼看起來不太高興？
Hey, Juichi!
充一
Who's prettier?
誰比較漂亮？
What? Naturally, you, miss.
什麼？當然是妳囉，小姐
S-- Since you're a woman.
因為妳是個女人
Okay! Should we go now?
好的，我們該出發囉
What's with her?
她是怎麼搞的？
This is, you know--
這只是…
Shut up.
你閉嘴
It's this way.
該往這裡走
You'll see the school building right in front.
你們會見到學校就在眼前
You know, if we can see it from here, then they can see--
如果我們從這裡就看得到學校 那他們也能夠看到…
I got it. I got it.
好了，我知道啦
We'll be back.
我們很快就回來
Don't mess with our stuff!
不要亂動我們的東西
I won't touch it.
我碰都不會碰
There are people who would, though.
但是某些人真的會亂翻我們的東西喔
That girl, right? The King of Hotels?
那個女孩，對吧？那位旅館大亨
I wonder how she's doing.
不曉得她現在過得如何
I hope she's good.
希望她過得很好
That's one giant hole for a place called the Walled Town.
對一個叫做圍牆小鎮的地方來說 這個洞也太大了吧
Right, coming in.
好的，進去吧
Wait for me, Sis.
等等我，姊
It's not just abandoned, it's wrecked.
這不只是廢棄屋，它還遭到破壞
It's already…
已經…
Yeah.
沒錯
It looks like people already lived here.
看來像是曾經有人住在這裡
Since it's such a mess, they must have moved out, right?
這裡既然如此髒亂 他們一定搬走了，對吧？
Then what about the breeding pigs?
那些種豬呢？
Let's look around some more.
我們再走走看看吧
Is anyone here?
這裡有人嗎？
You never watch where you're going.
你走路從來不看路
I was trying to be careful.
我已經很小心了
This sleeping bag is nice.
這個睡袋很不錯
Isn't it like they just disappeared? Leaving their things like this?
把東西就這樣留下來 感覺他們好像是突然消失的
So that's it.
原來如此
Maru, this journal is incomplete.
小丸，這份日誌不完整
Incomplete?
不完整？
The journal stops with only a date on this page.
這份日誌停在這一頁，而上面只寫了日期
This…
這…
What the--
搞什麼…
It got so cold…
變得好冷
Ouch. What was that for--
妳幹嘛推我啦
Sis?
姊？
Sis! The water!
姊，那個水！
The room!
是房間
Damn.
該死
Maru.
小丸
It's a Man-eater.
是食人者
It's gotta be close.
牠一定就在附近
Find it.
把牠找出來
My eyes
我的眼睛
are sticking shut.
就快要睜不開了
Above us! Sis!
在我們的上方，姊
So it was a Hiruko.
真的是蛭子
Damn it.
該死
That was really bad.
剛才還真驚險
A second longer and it would've killed us.
再多一秒，牠就會殺了我們
How did you know it was up there?
你怎麼知道牠在上面那裡？
Just somehow.
我就是知道
Somehow?
就是知道？
Let's run for it.
快跑
It's following us from above!
牠從上方跟著我們
Better not bump into it on the stairs!
最好別在樓梯上跟牠撞個正著
What are you doing? Come on!
妳在做什麼？快跟上
Sis?
姊？
Weren't we running away?
我們不逃了嗎？
It's doing it.
牠正在進行當中
I get it now.
我現在明白了
Just as I thought.
就跟我想的一樣
It's that kind of attack.
是那種類型的攻擊
No need to be scared now. I understand it.
現在不用怕了，我搞懂了
You get the upper hand when you surprise and freeze them in a small space,
一旦你出奇不意地把他們凍結在小空間裡 你便因此佔了上風
but when someone runs at you with a weapon before they freeze,
但若是有人在凍結之前 帶著武器追擊你的話
you're in trouble!
你的麻煩就大了
It's not here.
不是這裡
I can get in, but I can't find the core.
我進得去，但我找不到核心點
Half of it ran away. So that was its main body.
其中一半逃跑了，所以那是牠的主體
What should we do?
我們該怎麼辦？
You're leaving?
妳要走了？
Hey, Sis.
姊
This town is completely gone, Maru.
小丸，這座小鎮已經不存在了
We were only asked to confirm his safety.
他只要求我們前來確定嬰兒的安危
Like I can say it.
好像我說得出口一樣
Then I'll tell him.
那我來告訴他吧
That's fine, right?
可以的，對吧？
There was no one there?
那裡一個人都沒有？
No women either?
也沒有女人？
And there was a Hiruko.
而且那裡有個蛭子
A Man-eater was living there.
有個食人者住在那裡
So aside from the child,
除了那個孩子之外
even those I hated weren't there.
就連我憎恨的那群人也不在那裡了
A Man-eater turned it into a nest.
那裡成了食人者的巢穴
So it just means no one is living there.
也就是說沒人住在那裡了
The Man-eater could have started living there
食人者可能是在大家都離開了之後
after everyone moved, when the building got too old.
當建築變得老舊不堪時才開始住在那裡
Juichi, you can't lose hope.
充一，你不能失去希望
Hey! You three slant eyes!
喂，你們三個斜眼
Who's calling us weird names?
是誰在給我們亂取名字？
-Is it him? -Yeah, I'm sure.
-是他吧？ -對，我很肯定
It can't be--
不可能…
Look, see!
你們看
Aren't you Boar #11?
你是種豬11號嗎？
You're alive!
你還活著
Boar #6! And Boar #9!
種豬六號和種豬九號
Don't call us that!
別這樣叫我們啦
You're the one who said it first! I just copied you!
是你們先這樣叫我的耶，我只是有樣學樣
So, we're living somewhere else now.
我們現在住在別的地方了
The kid born from your seed is healthy!
用你的精子生下的那孩子很健康
-What? -Anyways, come see!
-什麼？ -總之，你親自過來瞧瞧吧
…and that's what happened.
就是這麼回事
Was it about a month?
大概在一個月前嗎？
It was a month after you ran away,
在你逃跑一個月後
and those two women had been executed.
那兩個女人被處決了
Your son started crying in the middle of the night.
你的兒子在半夜開始哭了起來
Who knows what those women would do if it annoyed them?
誰知道那群女人被惹毛之後 會做出什麼事？
So we all tried to quiet him.
所以我們合力試著安撫他
That's when
怪物就在那時
the monster invaded.
攻了進來
Because we were awake,
因為我們醒著
we were able to escape through the hole the monster created.
所以能夠從怪物製造出來的那個洞口逃跑
Look, Jugo! It's your dad!
你看，重吾，那是你爸爸
Not me. That way, Jugo.
不是我，是那裡，重吾
I said it's not me.
我說了不是我啦
He won't understand.
他不懂的啦
Good for him.
太好了
His enemies are all dead and his kid is okay.
他的敵人全都死了，但他的孩子沒事
Isn't it great?
實在太棒了，對吧？
Now I won't feel bad taking his money.
這樣的話，我就不用為拿了他的錢 而感到不好意思了
Why are you lying like that,
妳明明就哭了
when you're clearly crying?
幹嘛還要說這種謊話？
Shut up.
閉嘴啦
Hey, what else do we have?
我們還有什麼？
Boar meat, deer, mouse and a small bird.
野豬肉、鹿、老鼠和一隻小鳥
Let's just cook it all!
全都煮掉吧
Is it a big mouse? Small?
這算是大老鼠還是小老鼠？
-The small kind. -Did you kill it?
-小老鼠啦 -你殺了牠？
-No way! -Can I have a drink?
-怎麼可能？ -我可以喝一杯嗎？
-I want to cook that smoked meat I made. -That sounds good.
-我想煮我做的煙燻肉 -好主意
-It was so tasty. -Alcohol is--
-好好吃喔 -酒實在是…
Juichi.
充一
Eat. It's your welcome party.
吃吧，這是你的歡迎派對
I want to thank you for Jugo.
重吾的事，謝謝你了
They said you were taking care of him.
他們說是你在照顧他
Of course. He's your son.
不用客氣，他是你兒子
You know, Juichi--
是這樣的，充一…
So stupid. Stu-- stupid.
太蠢了，笨蛋
After freezing today, thank goodness for this.
今天被冷凍了之樣 能夠有這種享受實在太讚了
I'm so sleepy after that hot bath and eating my fill of meat.
泡了熱水澡，加上吃肉吃到飽 現在感覺好睏啊
What are we doing tomorrow?
我們明天有何打算？
Let's go find that Ibaraki facility.
去找那個茨城設施吧
How are we gonna find it?
要從何找起？
I've got an idea…
我有個主意
She fell asleep while talking.
她話還沒說完就睡著了
Lights out.
關燈
Wake up, Maru!
醒醒，小丸
Sis, this is…
姊，這…
There's no mistaking it.
絕對不會錯
Everyone get outside!
所有的人都出去
This cold is an attack by a Man-eater!
這股冷空氣是食人者的攻擊手法
Where's Juichi?
充一呢？
He's not here?
他不在這裡？
Juichi isn't here!
充一不在這裡
Calm down! You sure?
冷靜一點，你確定？
The leader and Jugo aren't here either!
隊長和重吾也不在這裡
Damn it! Where are you, Juichi? Get outside now!
該死，充一，你人呢？快點離開這裡
Juichi.
充一
He's just unconscious.
他只是失去意識
Here, take Jugo.
來，抱好重吾
Everyone! Get on the road and run around!
各位，快點到馬路上跑來跑去
If you don't keep moving, you'll die in a minute!
如果你們不保持移動，很快就會沒命
Stay calm.
冷靜
My head's so cold, it hurts!
我的頭好冷，好痛
I can still feel my legs.
我仍感覺得到我的雙腿
Something's wrong.
感覺不太對勁
I can't get away from the cold no matter how much I run.
不管我怎麼跑，就是離不開這股冷空氣
My lungs are freezing.
我的肺要結凍了
Is it chasing me?
牠在追我嗎？
Then why can't I see it?
那為什麼我看不見牠？
Or hear its footsteps?
也聽不到牠的腳步聲？
Damn it!
該死
The attack range I figured out earlier…
我早先以為的攻擊範圍…
Did I get it wrong?
難道是我搞錯了嗎？
Sis!
姊
The cold air is gone.
冷空氣消失了
You're good now! Sis!
妳沒事了，姊
-Don't go near him! -Let me go!
-別靠近他 -放開我
The baby's gonna die! Are you gonna let him die?
那個孩子會死掉 你要眼睜睜看著他死嗎？
No! That kid's the Hiruko!
妳弄錯了，那個孩子是蛭子
I know now since I've fought them a few times.
在跟牠們交手過幾次之後，我現在懂了
I can sense a Hiruko's presence.
我能感受到蛭子的存在
Sis. That kid is the one doing this cold attack.
姊，發動冷氣攻擊的是那個孩子
The cold is gone now.
冷空氣已經消失了
Like nothing happened.
彷彿什麼事都沒發生過
Okay, it's okay.
好了，沒事了
They said they can remove the thing inside me soon.
他們說很快就能夠移除我體內的東西
After that I can go back…
之後我就能回到…
…to school.
學校了
And I can see you, Kona.
我就能見到你了，小奈
I want to see you soon, Kona.
我好想趕快見到你，小奈
It'll be born soon.
馬上就要出生了
Dr. Sawatari!
猿渡醫生
It'll be fine.
沒事的
Jugo!
重吾
And this too.
還有這個
It expired ten years ago, but it's better than nothing.
已經過期十年了，但聊勝於無
Thanks.
謝謝
Is it really okay to take it?
我們真的可以拿走嗎？
We have more of the same medicine.
我們有類似的藥
Not that.
我說的不是那個
The car.
這輛車
I don't have a reason to travel anymore.
我沒有旅行的必要了
Besides, the car here is much better than mine.
況且，這裡的車比我的車好得多了
Yeah. You're right.
也是，你說的對
See ya, Juichi.
再見囉，充一
Careful you don't get frozen to death by your son!
小心別被你兒子凍死喔
What? Crap. That's weird.
怎麼會這樣？太怪了吧
-Sis? -I know!
-姊 -我知道啦
Let's go. Come on!
走吧，快點
No!
不行
What do you mean "no"?
「不行」是什麼意思？
Shut up, Maru!
閉嘴啦，小丸
Panicking won't make it work!
大驚小怪沒有用
Ah, geez!
饒了我吧
Everyone, we will be welcoming your new friends.
各位，我們即將歡迎一群新朋友的到來
This will be a very important time for you.
對你們來說，這是非常重要的時刻
Aim for the right future,
不管發生了什麼事
no matter what happens.
把目標放在正確的未來
Listen to your heart if you are confused.
感到困惑的時候，請聆聽自己內心的聲音
What a vague speech.
真是不知所云的一番話
Now please say hello to the new 5th years.
現在，向這群新來的五年級生打招呼吧
That night.
那一晚
The night I escaped.
我在那晚逃了出來
Someone broke out!
有人逃走了
Someone shouted out immediately.
立刻有人大吼大叫
Was I the traitor for escaping?
我是逃跑的叛徒嗎？
Is it a grudge?
這是個咒怨嗎？
I don't even know anymore.
我什麼都不知道了
But I do know one thing.
但有件事我很清楚
The one who killed Jugo's mother was--
殺了重吾的母親的人是…
Well,
那麼…
until next time.
下次見囉
What was that?
怎麼回事？
What? What? Inside the house?
怎麼搞的？屋子裡嗎？
I got it. I'm coming.
好啦，我去看看
Watch it, you damn idiot!
給我小心一點，你這個白癡
Hey, isn't that our car?
那不是我們的車嗎？